You're tuned to the drive on your 24/7
home of the black and gold Steelers
Nation Radio.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good afternoon, Steeler Nation. It's the
drive on a Friday. Wes Uhler, Matt
Williamson back in our studio palacious
home here on this Friday as we put the
bow on a
a wild week, a fun week, couple of days
out there for the owners meetings in
Arizona. Absolutely. I mean, we
laid it out quite well while we were
there.
Got home late Wednesday night and back
at it, but a lot different feel I mean
than where we were last time I saw you,
you Certainly was.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. Last time although the
weather's not too shabby here in Western
Pennsylvania, but
it's not quite the palm trees and
everything that was out there in
Arizona.
But yeah, we had had a lot of fun. We
told some of those stories. The owners
dinner was incredible. We got our swag
bags on the final day. I Nice. I went
through yesterday and took everything
out of the packaging and
>> Oh, I haven't taken out of packaging
yet.
>> tried it all on cuz I might have I might
have brought our guy TV one or two
things that were a little too big for me
and
>> yeah. in the in the Nike swag bag and
New Era and Fanatics and all the
different TaylorMade giveaways that we
got.
Matt, by my estimations, if you include
the clothes we got and the two really
nice bags
>> are nice, yeah.
>> it was like $1,200, $1,300
>> Nice pair of shoes, too. Nice pair of
shoes.
>> Right, right, right.
>> 11 or 12 different Nike shorts and pants
and shirts and polos and quarter zips
and hoodies and
>> I mean, for people that are watching,
it's a it's a normal sized duffel bag,
but it's you can't put like one more
thing in it.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, they pack it to the gills, you
know, right? It's like, thanks, that's
awesome. Plus a really nice duffel bag
from Fanatics,
a couple cool socks and hoodies and
shirts from New Era.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> socks on right now, actually. They're
insanely comfortable.
So yes, all the
all the selling that Matt Williamson did
to me of how cool these things were and
all that stuff.
I think I think maybe even undersold it
>> [laughter]
>> and it over delivered cuz it was my
first owners meetings. It was a lot of
fun. And the owners party as you said is
a really cool event, too. You know, you
see a lot of recognizable faces there
and you know, right?
>> Got to got to talk to McAfee for a
minute, which was which was fun.
Resisted the urge to go tell Joe Buck
that he needs to do more seasons of
Brockmire, which of course is the
fantastic television show with Hank
Azaria. So yeah, it was a it was a lot
of fun out there, but we're happy to see
our guy TV be back here in the studio.
And we have got plenty to hit on today,
Matt, as we always do.
>> Yeah. And this will really kick in, I
think, Monday when we come back, but the
draft is so soon. We are now [laughter]
like 21,
20 days 20 days away.
>> Yeah, yeah. Yeah, so yeah, it is 20 days
away, actually. So plenty to get to. We
will have our typical mock draft Friday
here.
Yeah, we haven't done one of those in a
while. We'll continue to do those on
Fridays and maybe even a little bit more
than that as we get closer and closer to
the draft. You know that we
will get to some tweets. We continue to
get a ton of those, which we love before
we get out of here. But Matt, we begin
and it has been a couple days since
we've done a show now. So some news of
the day items here that I think we just
>> Yeah. It's not a ton of news around the
league. I mean, people are starting to
buckle down and get in their war rooms
and build their draft boards officially
now. But there is a couple days since
we've chatted. I'm sure there's a couple
things we can go through. Might be the
might be the last of kind of the regular
news of the day segments here as as
things will get quiet as you just
mentioned a few times. Like everyone's
going to be hunkered down in their war
rooms and and getting ready for the
draft. Uh but we do know the dates have
been set for the Steelers mini camp and
OTAs.
>> Okay. Um of course the NFL off season is
divided into three phases. It actually
begins next week, April 7th with
voluntary workouts limited to strength
and conditioning. Keyword Before the
draft.
>> Yes.
>> Right, right.
>> Keyword being voluntary workouts there,
right? Limited strength
>> of an odd thing to me, too. Yes. Yes.
>> they can
I don't know if you know the answer
this, but I think any player that's
under contract can come in and use the
weight room anytime they want. Yes.
During the course of the year or some of
them are getting treatment and things of
that nature. I mean, I guess it's just
kind of a team building event, but I
always thought this was kind of an odd
one, you know, like I'm I'm working out
anyways or I'm I got my own schedule.
Why we even have this event?
>> Yeah. I don't know. Especially when it
is again, it's voluntary.
You know, I think it part of it is
probably just get everybody back
together, get everybody on the same
page.
>> Mhm. You get maybe a baseline of hey, if
there's someone like Broderick Jones
there, you know, chance
>> be helpful, yeah. you know, how how's
the neck and how's the recovery going
and all that stuff. But yeah, that will
begin next week, April 7th. And it's
probably the first time that some of the
new Steelers, Hoffman or whatever, works
out with the alignment or whatever, you
know. Yeah. Whoever shows up.
>> Absolutely.
The team is permitted to have two mini
camps this year, Matt,
with new head coach Mike McCarthy. You
get some wider Oh, yeah, okay. I haven't
thought about that for 20 years, right?
>> think about this for, you know, until
every few decades. But yes, so the
Steelers will have two mini camps, one
voluntary,
one mandatory. Okay? So the first
voluntary camp will be
actually in the lead up to the draft,
April 20th, 21st, and 22nd. Okay? So
those those three days there before the
draft.
>> the other team the Steelers would never
had in the last Exactly right. Exactly
right. Now, albeit still voluntary, but
an extra three days that you're allowed
there with a new head coach. And then
mandatory mini camp the first week in
June, June 2nd, 3rd, and 4th. That's a
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday. Okay.
And then, Matt, they also have their
traditional
10 OTA practices.
Okay.
>> If that makes sense. So you get you get
mandatory mini camp, you get voluntary
mini camp, and then you get the regular
slate of 10 OTA practices, which will
begin May 18th, run about three a week.
They'll have four in the last week, May
18th through June 12th.
Okay. So when was mini camp again? Um
>> Before that, right?
>> Mini camp is
is so sorry. It looks like it's going to
go OTAs
and then mandatory mini camp and then
another OTA session.
So they're going to kind of be
sandwiched there.
>> difference, folks, but not massively. If
you were sitting there at practice, you
wouldn't know the difference.
>> Yes. So 10 OTAs practices, three
mandatory mini camp, three voluntary
mini camp. It's going to be a little bit
of a chunkier
start of the the summer time than we're
used to now that they're allowed to do a
little bit more in the first year with a
new head coach.
>> Yeah, and if you recall last year, like
the first day of OTAs was Aaron Rodgers'
first day under contract and we
traditionally have broadcasted from
right there
next to the fields during OTAs and mini
camps as well. I assume we'll do
something along those lines and often
get a player straight from the field and
there is a lot of local media and it's,
you know, that they're they're wearing
helmets and they're doing football
stuff. But it's
I use this example and people get sick
of it, but I mean,
it's like
kindergarten through third grade.
>> [laughter]
>> You know what I mean? Like if if you can
get to camp and you're ready, you're
like graduated elementary school, we're
in pretty good shape, you know. Cam
Heyward doesn't need to go to elementary
school. But if as a team, it's like,
okay, let's get into like almost high
school level stuff when camp opens, you
know, like And a lot of it, too,
especially for the rookies and whatnot,
are
teaching them like, hey, we don't have
to go 8,000 miles an hour every rep and
teaching them the
>> Sometimes the mental side's more
important than the physical side.
>> don't be blasting your teammates. I know
you're trying to impress us and all
that, too. But there's an art to
practicing in the NFL with tempo and all
those things, too. Obviously, don't
touch the quarterback, but that's true
at all levels. But this is how we
practice as an NFL team. It's different
than where all of you came from, you
know.
>> Yes. Yes. And here's where you go for
your wide receiver meetings and Yeah,
they even that kind of stuff. That's a
kindergarten stuff, yeah. Here's where
you go for treatment and yeah, it's a
it's a whole kind of just laying the
foundation for Make sure you eat enough
here and hydrate here and that kind of
stuff, too, and you know, right? Yep,
and get to know your trainers and your
therapists and nutritionists and all
those people and your coaching and the
support staff and player development and
all that. It is. It's almost like an
orientation of sorts.
>> Yeah. You're not happy with your cleats,
you know, we'll get you settled out, you
know, right? Exactly right.
>> to do things like get their all their
stuff measured, too, you know, like the
helmet that fits perfectly and all those
things. Like again, Cam Heyward doesn't,
but you know, the new guys do, yeah.
>> [gasps]
>> So Matt, that was kind of the Steelers
news item of the day that I wanted to
discuss. Some around the league that we
have to talk about here. Um and Kirk
Cousins,
a Las Vegas Raider. Mhm.
I think
there's two parts of reaction of that to
me. The first is I think that's great
for Fernando Mendoza. That's the
that's the non-threatening
but respected veteran set of eyeballs to
show you how to be a pro extra, you
know, set of eyes to to bounce things
off of on the sideline when you come
back. And obviously a very capable
backup if something were to happen to
him injury-wise. And maybe even starts
the season for a month or so. I don't
think that's the way it'll happen, but I
think their head coach has said, we
don't want to put any young quarterback
in too early. Perfect. You know, right?
You figure that out as camp goes along.
Totally. Makes a ton of sense. They
also, I don't know either one and
certainly neither one knows me, but they
seem to have very similar personalities,
you know,
in a strange kind of way, Yeah, we
>> [laughter]
>> you know, they are kind of their own
beast, um, but they're very wholesome,
you know, and they they seem like they
would get along well, you know. Yes.
Yes. That's I think that's a good way to
put it. I think that's a very I think
that's a very good way to put it. So,
um,
that's the one half and then the other
half though is that, hey,
there you and I both agree that there
continues to feel a very kind of quiet
confidence around Aaron Rodgers' return
as the quarterback in Pittsburgh.
But now
the proverbial eggs are all in that
basket as as your other options have
really dried up. So, I'm not trying to I
don't know any of this. I'm not
spreading rumors on Steelers Nation
Radio or anything like that. But a lot
of people thought, man, you know,
Cousins signs right after Indiana's pro
day with the the Raiders.
And I don't think that had anything to
do with it. What I think had to do with
it is he pretty much realized the last
starting gig in the league in Pittsburgh
>> [snorts]
>> is probably not going to be available to
him. So, he took, you know,
a really, really
good backup option, you know, with with
an up-and-coming team, be around Tom
Brady, you know, mentor this kid, um,
made a decent buck doing it, too, you
know, so good for him. Yeah, so I
I think the writing's on the wall, just
reading the tea leaves, that Rodgers is
going to probably be a Steeler. I would
be I I think we both continue to be,
um,
on the same page in that regard. I think
we'd be surprised if Aaron Rodgers
wasn't a Steeler, but I also continue
there's always that small piece in your
mind that's like
until it's official,
um, you're going to think about it and
speculate on it a little bit and yeah, I
don't know if even Kirk Cousins would
have been plan B for the Steelers, but
your Seemed like a logical one.
>> plan B's are starting to get crossed off
the list.
>> Yeah, and even some of the national
people we talked to on the air at the
the owners meetings, I brought up Derek
Carr once in a while and they're like, I
don't think there's a lot of interest in
Carr right now around the league.
Cousins was kind of the last guy if the
Steelers weren't going to get Rodgers,
so it you know, you know, be a genius to
figure out the tea leaves here, you
know.
>> Exactly right. Exactly right.
Um, and yeah, so that's kind of,
um,
you know, where we're at and and that
one of the final quarterback dominoes I
think to fall this off season.
>> Last big name guy or potential starter
or you know, guy's had a a strong
career, you know.
>> Yes. Uh, Kyle Dugger has signed with the
Cincinnati Bengals. So, we wish him
well, former friend of the show, of
course,
called in here one time and then had an
interception two days later. We've had
We've had a knack for doing that.
Um, wish him all the best, of course,
except for those two games that he plays
against the Steelers. Um, so that was
something that I that I wanted to
mention.
Uh, and then Matt
>> I don't think it's a huge loss. I think
they've they've set themselves up to
move on from him. Right. And I don't
even think that we had thought there was
any chance that they were going to bring
him back, but I thought that was just
something that we should mention. Those
three older safeties, including what,
Peppers and Clark, I thought maybe after
the draft, right before training camp or
something, you might bring them in if
they're still out there, maybe, you
know, depending what the draft, you
know, entails, but all in all, the plan
was they were short-term fixes, you
know. Yes. Yes.
And then I guess kind of last notable,
Matt, and this is one of those
sometimes it's hard for us to comment on
stuff like this, but I think it's it's
it's very notable,
um, in that Puka Nacua has checked into
rehab. Yeah. Los Angeles Rams receiver,
um, according to his agent going to
rehab in an attempt to, quote, improve
his overall behavior in every aspect of
life, end quote, and he will complete
the program in time to be involved in
all of the Rams' OTAs. Uh, just never
something you want to hear. Hopefully
hope for all the best for him and
hopefully this is
um, a blip on the radar and doesn't end
up becoming something long-term.
>> Exactly. And there was some odd stuff
going on before this, obviously, and
maybe they're like you said, nip it in
the bud or I don't know the degree of
the issue or any of those things. First
and foremost, like a Maxx Crosby, who's
a great story of, you know, had a lot of
issues and now publicly addresses them
and is thriving, honestly.
>> It's a great example. Yeah, and
hopefully the same is true for Puka and
it works as a uh,
e- e- even as a
to show younger people, hey, you know,
just
>> Yeah. be public about it and then it's
okay not to be perfect. But you know me,
I mean, you got to reflect back on the
football side of it, too, is
after trading their second first-round
pick, the Rams now have the Falcons'
pick, which is 11 or 12 or 13, I
believe.
>> And I've said all along that the
responsible thing to do, and a lot of
these teams are like, oh, we're not
going to pick here very often. Well, the
Rams aren't going to pick there very
often. I mean, they've shown that over
and over.
>> Yes. The responsible thing to do is take
a tackle, cuz there's a shortage of
those guys. If you can get Freeling or
somebody like that, and just go get the
hard position.
But the irresponsible thing to do, and
this is before the Nacua thing, is
take the receiver and just try to win it
all this year. You know what I mean?
Like McVay even said it at the owners
meetings, we thought about trading
Davante Adams. I'm like, wow, I didn't
I'm shocked that he that those words
came out of his mouth, but he's only
around one more year. They're in it to
win it more than any team in the league.
And now
Nacua though
has to cloud this a little bit, just
because
JSN's contract just came down the pipe
and it is massive. massive. Well
deserved.
>> And Puka's agent's going to say, I want
that same deal plus 1%.
Okay, that sounds logical,
but can I
do I am I confident that I can give that
to you for your off-the-field issues at
the moment, you know? So,
I think they draft a receiver. Oh, man.
>> and which could be
a massive I mean, they could be a a
powerhouse offense. Yes, they could.
They certainly could. Maybe not their
choice of the first receiver there at
13, but certainly Leman or, you know,
right.
>> Yeah, could could definitely be one of
the top choices.
>> Mhm. Um, and yeah, now that that pick 13
for the Rams was always interesting, but
this this certainly adds another layer
to it.
>> Like I don't think they'll get Tate, but
they might get their choice in the
second guy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. If it's Tyson or who or
Concepcion or whoever they like, yeah,
right, right.
>> Very well could.
Um, so yeah, so that was, uh, kind of
the last notable thing. And then I guess
maybe we should we mentioned this very,
I think, briefly on our last, uh,
Tuesday show out at the owners meetings,
but one of the prospects that we've
talked about, have had a lot of
speculation about, Jermaine McCoy, the
Tennessee
>> yeah.
>> corner, who was maybe the best corner in
all of college football in 2024 as a
19-year-old, and then missed all of this
past season with a torn ACL, has not
played a college football game since he
lined up against Ohio State with Will
Howard and Jack Sawyer, um, you know,
when
15 months ago, however long ago that
was, we had mentioned how his pro day
was going to be massive for him, Matt,
and it was. Uh, ran a sub-44 40, 4.38
seconds, 38-inch vertical jump, 10-foot
7-inch broad jump, and, uh, the
the race for CB1 feels like it's
officially on between between him and
Mansour Delane. Yeah, and I think he's a
little bit bigger than Delane. I think
his best tape, which was a long time
ago, as you said, is better than
Delane's.
Um, now
I don't know this for I mean, again,
just because he participated one day for
half an hour or whatever, does not mean
his
his medical is clean as could be, you
know.
>> Sure. But maybe it is. You know, I mean,
obviously he he was able to do something
and do it very, very well. And that that
was a box that needed to be checked for
him to be in the top 20 conversation, I
think, let alone cornerback one. But
that doesn't mean that there aren't
still red flags, you know, he's still
working back. He was able to put have
one good day. That doesn't mean you can
have 17 good games or whatever, too.
>> Sure. Sure.
What I find interesting or
I think it was Michael Adesso, one of
our
One of our regular tweeters. Love shout
out there, Michael. I think he asked me
since we were together, would you
consider him at 21 if he fell?
And it's hard not to. Oh, I think it
would be very hard not to.
>> Yeah, I mean,
he I think people know me well enough
that I think it's receiver or line, or
line receiver, you know. And I do think
that's likely to happen. I think that's
the plan. But I think Omar's also set
them up well enough with so many picks
that if a luxury pick Downs, I mean,
Love, I mean, guys that I'm I don't
think have any chance to be there, are
there or within striking distance, they
could probably weather it.
>> It's at least a real conversation.
>> Yeah, right. I don't think outside
corner is a huge need, but then you
place him on the slot that doesn't
usually play the slot or whatever, you
know what I mean? Like he could be good
enough for me to say,
man, Who cares? Who cares, right, right,
right.
>> When I mean, when are we going to get,
you know, this guy
>> right. This guy could be a top five
corner in the NFL. Yeah, yeah, yeah. And
maybe we maybe we Play a lot of nickel
anyways, yeah, right, you know.
>> we did our our due diligence and we got
a guy who's going to be a top five, uh,
corner in the NFL in Joey Porter Jr.
Take two of them. That's a position
That's [laughter] a position where I'd
love to get greedy, man. You see what
the Seahawks did this past year.
>> like crazy and yeah, right, yeah, yeah.
>> elite pieces in that secondary.
>> Yeah. Um, I don't think it'll be an
issue. I think he's a top 20 guy.
>> the way he tested here. And if he
wouldn't have tested that way, then all
of the sudden you were not as confident
in taking him at 21.
Um, but yeah, I would certainly if we
were to make a short list of the okay,
here's the long shots that we think
there's no chance they're going to make
it to 21, but we'd be interested if they
did. I think
Jeremiah Love, Caleb Downs,
>> Especially at not positions that you're
expecting.
>> Sure.
He's he'd probably be on the list. Sure.
Yeah, and that's with Delane, but I
don't he's going to make it either, but
So,
my buddy Peacock and I for our podcast
have kind of a running joke going that
these mocks come out or I send out a
mock on either I did on Pro Football
Focus or whatever. Oh, that'll never
happen.
Probably not, you know. I mean, some of
the a lot of these things look
far-fetched when you read them in March.
Sure.
But
nothing's crazier than draft day.
I mean, no I mean, the best predictors
out there get like 10 picks right. You
know, these contests and things. Yeah,
it's like base like baseball. If you're
batting 300, you're doing really well.
Exactly. Our whole point is you think
things are weird or you that you know
what's going to happen, but you never
do. And it's chaos and it's it takes one
weird pick and then everything all the
dominoes get screwed up.
That's something that it feels like
happens just about every single year.
You got to prepare for it at least. And
and that's what that's what these things
are. It's really hard. We should
probably do it pretty soon.
We should probably do it pretty soon.
I might have to. Yeah. Cuz we're
probably done with, you know, picks and
what change
it takes some thought because McCoy's
going to be on there for sure. But
where? But probably pretty high, you
know, like I I would take him ahead of
like
Boston or somebody like that that I
like,
but this guy's a tier above him, you
know? So,
it gets to the but then you're like,
"Boy, now I'm short a receiver." You
know?
What do you value? Do you you going for
the position of need? You going for the
BPA? You trying to find a marriage
between the two? That's what makes all
these hypotheticals so much fun. Yeah,
maybe maybe next week we'll we'll I
think definitely next week we should do
our first first edition. It is it I
think for like the first
10 or so picks, it's like, "Oh, yeah, I
take Mendoza right here."
You know what I mean? I'm sure he'll be
one on both of our lists.
And maybe Reese is good enough he's two
even though you don't need him or you
play him off the ball or whatever, but
still
and and frankly those top six or seven
don't really matter cuz none of them are
ever going to make it, you know?
[laughter] But like Downs would be
pretty high. I think definitely be in
our top 10.
Without a doubt. Styles would be high.
Styles would be high. Certainly. The
wide receivers will probably be a little
bit higher. The offensive lineman will
be a little bit higher. Like I'm taking
a
quote lesser O lineman than the fourth
edge guy.
All edge guys. I'm not sure what I'd do
with Bane if he even makes my top 21. We
might only have like two of those guys
in our top 20, you know?
So,
some fun stuff certainly coming down the
line here as our focus gets
more and more so on the NFL draft. 20
days away, just a few miles from us
right here on the North Shore of
Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. There's our
news of the day, kind of our opening
salvo to get us started back on a Friday
here in at the studios putting a bow on
all of the week's proceedings. Wes
Uhler, Matt Williamson, it is the drive.
Steelers Nation Radio on the Steelers
Audio Network.
What's up, NFL fans? The NFL Draft is
finally here. And while you might not
know who your team is [music] drafting
this year, you do know your watch
party's number one pick, Bud Light. The
clean, crisp taste that has all the
scouts talking. Guess that's why it's
been the group's go-to draft beer season
after season. Be sure to order a round
for the table before your team's on the
clock. Bud Light, easy to drink, easy to
enjoy. Enjoy responsibly. Anheuser-Busch
Bud Light Beer, St. Louis, Missouri.
>> [music]
>> Back on the drive here as we roll along
on this Friday, Good Friday to all of
yinz out there amongst Steeler Nation.
Hopefully, if you're traveling around
this weekend any Easter weekend plans,
be safe, take care. Hopefully, the
weather is
turned here and we are ready for sunnier
and brighter days ahead.
And Matt, as we do that, we're kind of
walking that
balancing act, that tightrope of
looking ahead to the draft,
wrapping up some things from the
previous year, all of this. And one
thing that you had sent me
earlier this week that we wanted to make
sure to get to soon. It's not
necessarily time sensitive, but I think
something like this might come back up
in June, too. Just to remind people.
Right. Yeah.
But it is the NFL in 2025 last season
snap-weighted age by units. So,
basically, this is a massive breakdown
of how
old each roster is in the NFL. How old
each offense, each defense, each special
teams, each position group. And it's
broken down across the league amongst
all 32 teams. So, it's everything that
you do offense, defense positionally and
how your age groups stacks up to the
other 31 teams. So, this is to the
detail they
they
equate this
they do this equation. So, Used to Be
Football Outsiders, they were bought by
FTN Fantasy. So, I always like to give
credit to who does the work. But they've
been doing this for a long time
and it's amazing. I mean, because you
have to wait till after the year. It's
not
it's
So,
real dorks in football
>> [laughter]
>> will won't be like he's 27 years old.
They'll be like he's 27.2
years old. Not down to the month, but
they break it down to the next decimal
point.
And you know, you're only in the league
4 5 6 years, that kind of stuff matters.
And even like 27.1 versus 27.9, you
know? Kind of a difference, right? You
know, or draftable prospects, they'll do
that. So, they do that with every player
in the league, the exact age you are to
the day, you know? I mean, to the day of
and for how many snaps you're on the
field. Now, this is a bad example cuz I
don't want any bad mojo for Aaron
Rodgers, but for example, his first year
with the Jets,
he comes out as a starting quarterback
as I guess a 40-year-old at the time and
doesn't last long. So, even though he
was the starter, he'd only played a
couple snaps. So, those snaps for the
quarterback position for the Jets 2
years ago
would've been, okay, let's say it was
five snaps. It was even less than that,
I think.
That's 40.1 years old. But all the other
snaps at the quarterback position are 26
or whatever, you know what I mean? So,
Cam Heyward plays a lot of snaps as an
older guy. I mean, this really breaks it
down to the nth degree of who played
throughout the year and obviously
factors not who you wanted to play cuz I
mean, injuries factor in and who played
the youngest snaps at each respective
positions.
And
one thing that does skew it and Brady's
the perfect example, but Rodgers is,
too.
When you have a quarterback that's
really over aged or even under aged,
they they're going to play every snap
and let because they end up
and they carry an obscene amount of
weight because
there's not going to be a 42-year-old
running back on the Raiders or whatever,
too. You know what I mean?
Right. Right. It's the only position
that can get that old.
And these guys do even break down
special teams, but I care that much
about that. Right. Right. Right. But
yeah, if you have a quarterback that
plays 90% of the snaps like the Steelers
did, it's really going to skew your
overall and your offensive age. That's
the Right. I'm sure when they break it
down and I haven't looked this yet, but
when you break it down into positions,
the Steelers had to be the oldest in the
league. Had to be. They were pretty
close. On offense and on defense, they
were the I mean, just at quarterback, I
mean.
Yeah, they had to be the oldest.
Side note, folks, and I think this is a
misconception, too.
Yes, you'd love to have the youngest
roster. You know, like the Packers for
three or four years in a row were like
the youngest in this one.
But if it never comes to fruition, it
doesn't really matter. And
being old isn't as big a deal as it used
to be because so many of these are like
one-year deals. I mean, if you sign a
30-year-old
center and he plays one good year for
you and you get high-quality
return on the field and then he leaves,
that doesn't mean you're an old team.
You know what I mean? And you draft a
center the next year or you drafted one
in waiting in the wings to learn from
that guy.
So, some of it I mean, but it does
really break down of how old you were
per snap, not per game. I mean, to the
lowest common denominator, which to me I
think is really valuable. You know, at
least they think they don't think they
analyze, you know? I completely
completely agree with you. And so, let's
just kind of the the quarterback that
you mentioned there.
The average age of the Steelers
quarterback taking a snap this season
was 40.7 years old. Okay, that's a
perfect way to phrase it. That's the
average age of the quarterback.
Aaron Rodgers was 41 into 42 this
season, but he didn't take every snap.
So, Mason Rudolph's the game that he
started and and a few of the like when
he came in in relief and at the end of
the game. That's one snap to kneel at
the end of the game. That's 1/60th of
that game or whatever it is. Right. So,
the Steelers were the longest in the
tooth at quarterback substantially. The
the Raiders were 37 years old on
average. Or sorry, the the Rams, pardon
me, cuz Matthew Stafford
being you know, being the oldest.
Raiders were 34. Geno Smith played
pretty much every snap. Kenny, you know,
I think Kenny had a game in there.
And maybe O'Connell got out there a
little or something. Yeah. Cincinnati
had the third oldest average age because
Joe Flacco played so many snaps at the
quarterback position. But yeah, the
Steelers uh pretty substantially there
the oldest at quarterback as you can as
you can imagine.
>> And as I kind of mentioned before, I
almost think quarterback shouldn't be
equated with the rest of the offense.
They just play so much. They're a little
bit of an outlier.
>> That's why too. So the Steelers had on
average their total snap weighted age by
offense was second oldest in the NFL,
27.8, only behind the Washington
Commanders who had the oldest.
But so much of that is weighted by Aaron
Rodgers who played
I mean it had to be him or Zach Frazier
who played the most snaps on the offense
this season, you know.
>> They they didn't miss many. Right. So
that obviously brings the age up for the
Steelers 20. And now this one I don't
think is surprising, Matt. The Steelers
had
>> before you get there.
>> Yep. The Russell Wilson year
if you looked at the offense, it was
very young. And I know Fields played
some that year too. But the Steelers
weren't considered one of the youngest
in the league because Wilson played
uh 75% of the snaps or something that
year.
>> in his mid 30s.
>> in his mid 30s where you had the
Frazier, I mean all those young old
linemen that played a ton of snaps.
>> Totally. It he outweighs all those guys
just in terms of the math. That makes
sense.
Um so Steelers second oldest offense on
average, second oldest defense on
average, Matt. Uh I don't think
>> adds up. We know it's expensive and it's
old, you know.
>> of the third third third third oldest on
So second oldest offense, third oldest
defense. Defense only behind the
Commanders and the Where is it here?
Minnesota Vikings. Okay. So Washington
actually had the oldest average age on
offense, oldest average age on defense,
and they weren't very good. That's not a
great spot to be. So again, this is the
first I've really looked at this, but
that doesn't shock me at all. And not
that I'm super smart or anything like
that. But after the Daniels rookie year
when they went to the final four
I thought they really thought they could
run before they could walk.
>> They brought in a bunch of veterans.
>> and Ertz and all these dudes like oh
we're we're a final four team. We got
the young quarterback. Yeah, you got the
young quarterback, but you're not as
close as you think. And then all of a
sudden you get old before you know it.
And it's like man, here they traded for
Debo, traded for Tunsil, didn't have any
infusion of draft picks and frankly, you
who knows how much
who knows how much the Steelers upcoming
draft class will play. They may not play
many snaps. But you're going to have a
lot of people on the roster that are
young.
>> Yes. You know, that are coming that
aren't on the team as as we speak. They
might play a ton of snaps, they might
play none, you know, who knows.
San Francisco third on this list, Matt.
Um
oldest
uh
oldest offense
Wait, hold on one second here. This
Okay, sorry. Uh yeah, San Francisco
oldest offense really weighed them down
uh because
>> Trent Williams, Christian McCaffrey,
George Kittle, all those guys all those
guys in their 30s.
>> position or all pretty old. Atlanta had
the fourth oldest average uh team in the
league, fifth oldest offense, 16th
oldest defense.
>> Okay. Uh Minnesota number five overall.
Uh Denver number six, Buffalo number
seven, Colts number eight. So
>> Okay. when I look at that, I look
through that list of the top eight
oldest teams
and man
a side Denver certainly was a contender.
They were in the AFC Championship game.
>> Buffalo you could probably put into
that. Yeah, that too. I mean they're
perennial.
But and then well I guess San Francisco
did win a playoff game as well. So three
of the top eight oldest teams won a
playoff game. Steelers made it to
before, Colts missed, Washington missed,
Atlanta missed, Minnesota missed. So of
the eight oldest teams, four made the
playoffs, four did not qualify. So you
certainly don't want to be old and bad.
Now if you only have one or two guys if
like a Rodgers factor
you you got to you got to you do have to
look at it more than just the
spreadsheet.
But old and bad is scary.
>> [laughter]
>> You know, like Minnesota comes to mind
because their quarterbacks were young.
It was McCarthy, you know, wasn't like
they had an old dude, you know, Cousins
or something for a year.
So they were collectively pretty old.
You know, it wasn't just one guy
dragging them down. And Atlanta is a
little concerning, but a lot of that is
because of Kirk Cousins.
>> Cousins played a fair amount.
>> Cousins did play a fair amount.
Um so those were kind of the top eight
oldest.
>> Okay. Um and then if you go what really
kind of caught my eye when I was looking
uh through this, Matt youngest average
age team in the league was Green Bay,
about 25 and a half.
>> five years in a row they've been there.
>> That's like it's almost like something
that they're trying to do. Well, they
don't bring in a lot of free agents from
outside the organization and they don't
have that one or two dudes that's been
there for 15 years. Yeah.
Uh Green Bay youngest, New York Jets
second youngest, Philadelphia
>> promising for the Jets at least. Right.
>> so, certainly.
>> We know that they're trying to rebuild
and play young guys.
>> They had the youngest offense in the
league, 26th oldest defense in the
league the Jets did. Okay. Eagles third
youngest
Super Bowl champion Seattle Seahawks
fourth youngest
>> Wow, that's great.
>> Carolina Panthers fifth youngest.
They're pretty successful team.
>> So what really stood out to me there,
Matt, is that of the five youngest
teams, four made the playoffs, right?
Seattle won their division, Carolina won
their division, Philly won their
division, Green Bay was a wild card, one
won the Super Bowl.
So I mean again, [clears throat] this is
a one-year sample size.
>> Of course. But I look at the top
>> like Green Bay didn't have Kraft and
Micah Parsons and you know, like they
lost some things.
>> I look at the top eight oldest teams and
I'm like, okay, Denver yes, Buffalo
maybe, but you can go with maybe one and
a half of those eight teams were a true
bonafide contender.
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah.
>> playoff team. Steelers were a playoff
team. I don't think the Steelers were
contenders.
>> I don't I don't I don't think Carolina
was a contender.
>> Exactly right. But here
of these bottom five, you get four
division champions. Carolina a little
bit of an outlier because I think we all
agree they were not a contender,
although be it still a division
champion. At least the organization is
trending the right way in terms of a
youth movement, you know. Seattle
certainly a contender, won the whole
dang thing. Philadelphia I think a
contender as much as things are
cantankerous there. They were just in
the Super Bowl, you know, a year ago and
were a division champion. Green Bay
>> a couple older dudes, you know. Green
Bay you and I at one point I think both
would have picked them to be the Super
Bowl winner maybe in the middle of the
season before
>> was running wild.
>> was running wild and Parsons was looking
the part and all that. Um now they fell
apart due to some injuries. Uh but man,
that And again, this is only a one-year
sample size, so I don't want to make it
seem like it's gospel.
>> Of course. And these rosters do get
overhauled. I mean it's like 30 or 40%
of the rosters across the league get
changed. That was just kind of four of
the five youngest teams division
champions, one of them won the Super
Bowl. I mean it's it's a young man
There's a reason that you hear so often
it's a young man's game. It's a young
man's game.
>> Yeah. Yeah, and I mean if you're see if
this was Seattle Nation Radio, it'd be
like, hey, can we build a dynasty here?
You mean our biggest competitors the
Rams, they're one of the oldest teams in
the league, can they keep it up as long
as we can?
>> Niners one of the older teams in the
league too.
>> great point. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. So
>> we're the best chance to be still strong
two, three years from now, you know.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Um so that was just
you had sent that to me. I thought that
that was very interesting and just, you
know, kind of deserved combing over
here. Yeah. Um Curious where the west
rest of the division comes in because I
know the Browns played the most
rookie snaps of any team in the league,
which shouldn't shock anybody. I mean
they had a good rookie class at
positions that were easy to play,
Judkins, Fanin, etc.
So they at least dedicated themselves to
being young.
>> They had the 12th youngest offense in
the league. Okay. Defense a little bit
older,
25th. So So they were
>> They were the 20th oldest overall. So a
little bit younger than below I mean
little younger than average. little
younger than average. Cincinnati 19th.
So Cincinnati and Cleveland were both
about the same.
Um Cincinnati
>> Flacco definitely hurts that equation.
But both of them actually cuz he got
traded from one to the other. [laughter]
It's true. That Although did he He
started the season Did he start the
season for Cleveland? I'm trying to
remember.
>> week one. Well, maybe he did. He played
three or four games.
>> so. And then
>> Remember Tomlin was like, who's trading
this guy in the division, right? Yeah,
yeah.
>> they gave it to to Dylan Gabriel. So
Cincinnati 19th uh oldest overall,
Cleveland 20th. Uh so both of them kind
of below the league average. And then
Baltimore was 26th. So one, two, three,
four, five, six. They were actually the
seventh youngest on average
uh in the National Football League. And
all And that with Baltimore had the
oldest average special teams in the
league. Tucker.
Yeah, yeah, I would think that had a lot
to do with it.
>> So
um
interesting. Baltimore's average age uh
for the entire
>> them all last year?
>> I don't think No,
no. Because they He was first year
without him. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um
But Baltimore's average age for the
entire roster for the season per snap
26.3.
Okay. Uh Cleveland and Cincinnati were
26.6
and the Steelers were 27.8.
Okay.
So Frank I mean just to be honest, if
this was Ravens Nation Radio
I would be saying I like our chances of
being the most competitive team in the
division for the next couple years. You
could be like, those Steelers are
relying on the Haywards and Watts and
Ramsays, how long are they going to last
and who's their next quarterback? Where
the Ravens, I'm trying to think if
there's I mean it's off the top of my
head
guys they truly count on for a lot of
snaps that are 30 plus.
Andrews
then it's pretty short. You know I mean
like most of their dudes are probably
mid to late 20s. I don't think they've
drafted great since Ozzie Newsome.
>> They have the oldest running back snap
average
>> Oh, okay. I didn't think Henry, that's a
great one. Yeah.
I don't want to say substantially, but
very, very clearly the oldest average
running back age at 29.
>> Yeah, and got good production out of
them, obviously.
>> Yes. Oh, San Francisco right there, too,
because of because of McCaffrey. Makes
sense. But those two kind of an outlier
>> class. where everyone else in the
running back group is like 23, 24, 25,
>> to be like the youngest position group
across the board.
>> pretty much so. Yeah, and it it it looks
like if I'm looking here, yeah, running
back and wide receiver, the youngest the
youngest position groups
pretty unanimously across the league all
in about the mid-20s there, give or take
a little bit.
>> Okay. So, that was interesting.
>> Yeah, it's an interesting exercise. You
know, like again,
I like that they also have a
a spreadsheet, a grid of okay, there's
one position that's super old or one
that's super young, but collectively is
it a young team? Is it an old team? And
some teams in
this also pivots off the other thing
that this organization does is they do
snap weighted injuries, too.
>> Yes. Like if you were hit super hard by
injuries, maybe you were younger than
you wanted to be. You you played guys
that weren't ready. You put you're
throwing that fourth rounder out there
cuz you get two injuries ahead of them
and he wasn't ready. Exactly right.
Exactly right. So, um and we do have
those numbers, too, all those injury
numbers. Maybe we can we can get to some
of those on the other side here. We're
overdue for a break.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Uh but that was I I I liked reading
through that when you sent it to me and
I just I thought that was a fun
conversation to have here
>> Yeah. on this Friday.
>> That's one of the ones where you it's
you look at the the two ends of the
spectrum and then you look why. You
know, it's cuz again, Rodgers has a ton
to do with this season, right?
>> makes a lot of sense. Makes a lot of
sense. Let's get to a break here. We'll
come back. We'll close down the first
hour of the show when we return. Wes
Uhler, Matt Williamson, it is the drive
on a Friday, Steelers Nation Radio on
the Steelers Audio Network.
>> [music]
>> Final segment here of the first hour.
Two beefy ones, Matt. Yeah. Much like
the uh
>> I think we have much to talk about. We
were rolling along there.
>> Much like the beefy burritos that we had
out in Arizona.
>> We did have some Mexican We'll get to
that one. We'll get to that more here in
just a second.
>> right across the street was lovely. I
could I go right now.
>> Well, let's talk about it a little bit
more because
>> [laughter]
>> uh we we two beefy segments. We need a
shorty here to get our clock back on
schedule for hour two. Sudesh tweets us,
"Welcome back. In your dream scenarios
of everything fell perfectly, who would
be the Steelers first round pick?" Also,
uh yesterday was National Burrito Day.
What was your favorite Mexican meal in
Arizona? Was it chicken, beef, or pork?
Okay, which one do you want to start
with there? I
The place across the street was really,
really good and super convenient.
>> called Blanco. But the our last Mexican
meal was probably the best one. Yes. And
we went downtown Phoenix and it was
phenomenal. It was called Dos Dos Maya
something like that. But a meal from
Steelers video was found it, yeah. Found
it and it was like one of the highest
rated places and got us a reservation
and all that. It was amazing.
>> So, mine was crab then because I got
crab and blue crab enchiladas there and
they were phenomenal. I I had the um I
had the
>> Yours just fell off the bone.
>> Mine just fell They literally brought me
like a pork leg. Yeah.
>> And you like And [laughter] it just like
was
>> the bone.
Sauces and tacos and beans and
>> Yeah. Yeah, so I think I would go with
pork. Uh mine mine was pork. Yours was
One fellow we were with got duck that
looked incredible, too, at that meal.
>> Right, right, right. So, that was
I I don't think any of the the choices
Well, you know, pork was on the list,
right? On the tweet. Yeah.
>> were all They were all so good. We this
place across the street from our hotel
>> Oh. This place across the street from
our hotel. So, we got in later Saturday.
Mhm. Um and so we were all we got to the
hotel, got checked in, and it was
probably 7:00 or 8:00 at that point.
>> pretty worn out and
>> worn out and by our clock it's like 9:00
or 10:00 East Coast time and we're all
starving, haven't had dinner yet. We
went over to this place across the
street and had an awesome dinner. It was
so good that Matt and I went back for
lunch on Sunday.
>> [laughter]
>> Yeah. 3 years before Dale and I did it
twice, too. Yeah, right. And I think the
video guys went one other time without
us. They went with one with us and one
without us. So, we weren't there that
long to hit the same restaurant twice.
>> Oh. Right across the street. So good.
>> So good. The Mexican food was amazing.
Uh dominoes fall, who would be my the
Steelers first pick in my dream
scenario? I mean, Fernando Mendoza.
Yeah, so yeah.
>> might be a little too far-fetched, I
think.
>> you said like in a dream world. I mean,
Downs, but he's not going to fall. I
mean, like that's too crazy.
>> scenario I think you take Mendoza out of
it. You take Downs out of it. You take
Tate out of it cuz maybe that's the
answer.
>> too. Same with Styles, same with you
know.
>> I don't know. Magoa? Maybe. Magoa, yeah.
Cuz he could be tackle guard. I mean,
you put him at left guard, he may never
leave. I I really like him. I I think I
think I think mine, if we're going
realistic, would probably be one of the
offensive line cuz I can't say Tate.
That's not realistic. Like that is a
dream scenario.
>> Of course. But yeah, my my dream
scenario would be
Yeah.
>> I'm think I'm I'm really warming up to
that idea.
>> Yeah. I think Fano might be every bit
the guard Vega is.
But the fact that maybe he's a tackle
would would beat that tie for sure.
Yeah.
I mean, he's a real movement based guy
and that's what this offense wants, too.
>> It's a tough one because like if if I if
we thought a little bit more of Ti
Simpson, that could be the easy answer,
you know? I think he'll be there and you
you know, damn. Yeah. That's a it's a
it's a weird it's a weird one for it's a
weird class in that regard because most
of the quote-unquote blue chip guys
are non-traditional positions of value.
Like the Downs and the Loves and you
know, Sunny Styles. I mean, I just I
don't I think even in a dream scenario
it's not realistic to say that those
guys are there.
>> I know we don't have a lot of time, but
you got but you know that I've followed
the draft now for
long time. at least 45 years. You know,
and as intently as an 8-year-old can or
a 6-year-old.
>> [laughter]
>> And there's been many Steeler most
Steeler drafts where especially when I
was a young kid where I'm like holding
on for dear life. Like I hope that dude
falls. Like I remember the year Tory
Holt, David Boston, and Edwards came
out. The Steelers were definitely taking
a receiver and I'm like, "Man, if they
get Holt or Boston, I'd you know." And
then they both fell. I'm like, "Okay,
they'll get Edwards." You know, like the
dream scenario was Holt or Boston, you
know, like didn't happen, but that
wasn't that far-fetched. You know, this
one it's I don't know who that guy is.
There's not that dude like "Boy, if the
Ravens pass on this guy, they might get
him." Like I remember jumping out of my
skin when they got Rod Woodson. Yeah, of
>> [laughter]
>> course. I was like, "What? I can't
believe that." Like I wouldn't have
believed that. I mean, they had like the
10th pick in the draft, the ninth pick
in the draft. They got Rod Woodson. I
can't believe it. He might be the best
one in the draft.
>> Yeah.
Hour in the books, another hour to go.
Let's do some mock draft conversation in
hour number two
when we return. Halfway home here on a
Friday, Wes Uhler, Matt Williamson, it
is the drive, Steelers Nation Radio on
the Steelers Audio Network.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Good evening, Steeler Nation. How we
doing? Well, that's good. Us, too. Hour
number two here of the drive on a
Friday.
>> I know. I guess it doesn't count from
when you were in in Arizona. Uh well, in
that I guess Yeah. We do things a little
differently when we're on location.
>> No doubt.
>> We do a bonus hour. Um we're kind of
moving and shaking and trying to grab
guests and there's not as much
There's not as much static nature of the
show. And you know, Matt being 3 hours
away earlier, I was afraid to get my
signals crossed with is it actually
morning or afternoon or evening?
>> It was always just bright out and nice
when we were recording, so it didn't
feel like good afternoon at all or good
evening. Yeah, right.
>> at that time it's like it's like 3:00 in
Arizona, but it's 6:00 here, you know?
>> ate breakfast and bacon and eggs like 2
minutes before that, right? Matt
[laughter] and I
And speaking of which, Matt called this
when we He was like, "There's going to
be great breakfast." He's like, "It's
the complete At the combine, we've
shared these stories. We have to walk 15
minutes round trip just to get water
at the combine."
>> And frankly, the food's not even that
good in the media room, either. It's
like pre-made box sandwiches.
>> and it's hard to complain about free
food.
>> Right.
>> But the water and the coffee, you got to
walk I'm not kidding, 15, 20 minutes
round trip just to get a water or a
coffee. And the coffee is terrible.
Whereas at the owners meetings, it's
like a five-star breakfast. It's great
coffee.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> And Matt was like, "Dude, you got to get
some of the juice." He's like, "It's
really good."
>> And Matt's like, "Dude, you got to get
some of the juice. It's all fresh
pressed. It's all like local citrus."
So, we're slugging down orange juice and
grapefruit juice and it's like the
freshest. It's like they just squeezed
it in the back.
>> and pineapple and all that stuff was
really good, too, and yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unbelievable.
So, yeah, we were just kind of in a
happy sunshine Mexican food margarita
stupor for for four solid days out there
>> [laughter]
>> and unaware if it was the morning, the
afternoon, or the evening, but we're
getting back to That last day we were on
a mission. We're like, "We're getting
our
stuff that we're getting in there and
getting our
our free gifts. Then we're going to have
an awesome breakfast and then we're
going to have 3 hours of
kick butt radio. All right. And we
nailed it.
>> peeled back the curtain on how Tuesday
morning went down. [laughter]
It was just mind over matter for this
guy, right?
>> Matt Matt was dealing with some stomach
stuff and you know, wasn't feeling his
best on Monday. So, Tuesday morning Matt
and I were going to leave the hotel at
8:15 to head over. I text Matt a little
after 8:00 and I'm like, "Hey, I'm ready
if you want to roll early, just let me
know." Matt texts me, he's like, "I'm
I'm I'm already down here. I'm ready to
go, you know, let's let's do it."
>> Probably had a couple of Couple of other
choice words in there, but
>> [laughter]
>> Right. This is a family program. Uh I
get down I get down there. Matt and I
are waiting for our Uber to take us to
the uh to take us to where the the
meetings are. And Matt looks at me as
serious as can be and he goes, "All
right, here's how today is going to go."
>> [laughter]
>> He goes, "We're going to get dropped
off. We're going right to the rep room.
We're getting our Nike swag bags and all
our free stuff.
>> Yep. Then we're going to have an
awesome, delicious breakfast. Then we're
going to do a kick-ass radio show like
we always do.
>> right. And then we're going to go eat a
bunch of Mexican food and drink a gallon
of tequila and enjoy our last night in
Arizona." It's exactly how the day went.
>> exactly how the [laughter] day went.
Right. We get there, we're the first
ones at the swag room and
>> We're running over any obstacles in our
way. This is how the day's going to go.
Boom, let's take care of business.
>> Matt was like that famous interview with
Marshawn Lynch where they're like,
"Well, what do you do if this happens?"
And he's like, "I run through a mhm
chest." Right. [laughter] Right.
>> what if they do this?" "I run through a
dude's chest."
>> Right. "I just keep running through a
dude's chest until it's over and it's
over and
>> was going to go, right.
>> over and it's over and eventually that
dude's not standing there anymore.
That's how the day went. So, after like
3 days of striking out, Matt and I
finally get into the merch room. We get
our It had to be $1,200 worth of Nike
stuff.
>> Crazy stuff. Duffle bags and shirts and
polos and hoodies and pants and shoes
and socks and all kinds of stuff. Uh we
have an awesome breakfast. We do an
awesome show as always. And then we had
a really nice dinner and kind of final
evening there. Brought it on home.
Brought it on home. Willed it to
existence. Matt willed it into existence
and it was delightful. Uh but now we are
back to kind of our standard operating
procedures here and in studio and all
that for the next few weeks, of course,
until the draft will throw another
monkey wrench into our scheduled
programming. Part of our scheduled
programming over the last uh month or
so, maybe I think ever since the
combine, so maybe the last 5 6 weeks,
has been a Friday mock draft. Yeah. You
people love it. I'm not going to lie, it
is fun for us. It's a good exercise, but
it's also an easy kind of I know, all
right, final hour of the show's on
Fridays. We're going to do a mock draft.
It's a nice a nice exercise to lead us
into the weekend.
Matt, we're going to do that now. We're
going to do four rounds here today.
And I think you and I both agreed we did
some trades the last couple times we've
done this, so we just want to stay
static here.
Yes.
I'm I'm not saying trading down is
cheating, but it's a little bit of a
cheat code especially in this draft
because there's almost rarely is there
one name that just stands out so far
above the rest in this particular draft.
I can't believe he's there, let's jump
on him. There's five that you would
like. And okay, moving down's great, you
pick up more stuff and you probably get
one of those dudes. I just don't think
many teams are going to be looking to
trade up this year, either. And and I
don't want to trade down every draft
because
you end up with more resources than you
probably deserve. And I I think you're
spot-on. This feels like a year where
everyone's going to want to trade back.
Yeah. And there's not going to be the
dancing partner to move up because
there's not five quarterbacks with
first-round grades on them like we've
seen in some years and things like that.
So, let's do this one with no trades
from our standpoint. We're going to stay
pat at pick 21. Yep. Mendoza off the
board to the Raiders. Ar'vell Reese off
the board to the Jets. Those are
starting The first one certainly very
chalky, but Reese becoming pretty chalky
as well.
>> I think he'll be too. Sunny Styles third
to Cardinals and Jeremiah Love fourth to
the Titans.
>> Okay. No shock so far.
>> No shock so far. Carnell Tate goes fifth
to the Giants. I don't think I don't
think that'd be a shocker.
>> Not bonkers. I would take Styles if I
were them, but he's gone, so I think
that's a fine consolation prize. Help
your Help your quarterback build a nest
around Dart, okay.
And then here, Matt, the Jets move up
with the Browns. They trade their 16th
overall pick and their 33rd pick, the
start of the second round,
>> to Cleveland for pick six. Cleveland
moves back 10 spots.
>> I think Cleveland would love to trade
down. I I don't think there's a home run
for them at six.
>> I think they would love this.
>> Tate even if Tate was there.
>> Yeah. Uh and so the Jets, after taking
Ar'vell Reese second, take Ruben Bain
Jr. sixth. Wow.
>> Now again, I don't know how realistic
that would be to take two edge rushers
and both in the top six.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> But Ruben Bain is going to go early and
would So, for that It I mean the fact
that he's off the board, right. Right.
Right. They picked up McDonald's
fifth-year option. I doubt they would
take two edges with all their needs, but
hey, this kind of fun.
Number seven, Caleb Downs goes to the
Commanders. I think they would I would
think they'd be very happy with that.
>> be very happy with that. Second wide
receiver goes off the board to New
Orleans. Makai Lemon is a Saint
>> Wow.
>> at pick eight.
>> early, but I understand it. Again, help
Shock. Help
Build that nest after your quarterback.
>> line pretty much in place. You got
Olave. Number nine, David Bailey, edge
rusher out of Texas Tech, goes to the
Chiefs. Now, that's I think they'd
sprint to the podium for that.
>> to the podium for that.
>> He plays a lot of leads. He's perfect
for that. Number 10, the Cincinnati
Bengals on the clock. They take Mansour
Delaine, corner out of LSU.
>> Okay.
Again, I don't think any good defensive
player is a bad pick for Cincinnati, but
I really think linebacker up the
middle's their real weakness. Corner's
actually probably the best position on
the team on the defense. Not that they
couldn't use another one, but I think
they would love it if someone like Sunny
Styles or Caleb Downs fell to them.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And then that might be tough
at 10. At 11, the Dolphins take Jordan
Addison. So, three wide receivers off
the board in the top 11 in this edition
Okay.
>> of the mock draft. That's something we
haven't seen quite to that extent. So,
on my other podcast, my Locked On
podcast,
um
my co-host did a a mock and you know, we
always talked through it and he had
the
Dolphins take Sedeeq and a wide receiver
with their first two picks. Okay. Which
I thought made all the sense in the
world, you know, there's Willis, blah
blah blah. And I don't want to get too
far into this. This is not a Dolphins
show.
But the Packers are really
the Packers brass moved to South Beach,
>> [laughter]
>> you know.
And
>> They upgraded the weather certainly
substantially.
>> The Packers have some real strong draft
tendencies.
Never take wide receiver in the first
round except for last year.
And
pretty much they went like 12 of 13
years defense defense except for Love.
So,
I don't know that they will necessarily
be taking pass catchers galore there.
That might be a fill-in-the-blank
situation, but their pass catchers are
by far the worst in the league. Yeah.
They definitely need help there. That's
for sure. Pick 12, the Cowboys take
Spencer Fano. Tackle/guard out of Utah.
>> Okay. I don't see that. I think it'll be
defense, but okay. The fact he's off the
board I think is notable.
>> 13,
Francis Mauigoa goes to the Rams.
That'd be interesting. I mean, how would
you pass on that at that point, right?
>> he's I think definitely and then there's
a little run of offensive linemen here
is Viliami Fehoko Ioane Mhm. ends up in
[clears throat] Baltimore. Man, that'd
be That's a big landing spot for him to
me, yeah. It'd be a lot like when
Linderbaum ended up there and I was
like, "No, come on, anywhere but there."
Uh 15, Kendre Miller, edge rusher out of
Auburn, goes to the Bucks. Good. Want
him Want him to fall.
>> Want him to fall or want him to go off
the board. Um and then 16th, the Browns,
remember cuz they swapped with the with
the Jets.
>> pick, yeah. They take Monroe Freeling,
tackle out of Georgia.
>> him where they were sitting before.
That's how That's why trading back looks
so attractive.
And I just don't think many teams are
going to be in the market to trade up.
>> Same. Same.
17, Dylan Horton, safety out of Oregon,
goes to the Lions. Mhm. 18, Avyon
Terrell out of Clemson. So, second
corner off the board is Terrell.
>> okay. Uh goes ahead of McCoy to
Minnesota. Pick 19, Keidron Smith is a
Carolina Panther.
And then this one makes a lot of sense
for Dallas. At pick 20, they go
Adetomiwa Adebawore, edge rusher out of
Miami. Okay.
So, McCoy is still there. We are I like
how this played out because it's been
vastly different than our other
exercises because
there's not really other than Lomu and
he even I don't know profile's what
we're looking for.
>> think he can play guard this year.
>> Cuz I don't think he can play guard this
year.
So, We never talk about him, but I think
he's a pure tackle and that means he
sits around for a year, does nothing.
>> I think it's a little too high for us to
take Matt Mad Max here, Eyioma
Uwazurike.
And so, a lot of the other offensive So,
I like how this played out because
there's two you don't need them, but
wow, what a steal. Yeah, I was trying to
think who else was a safety or corner.
>> So, I basically I I can read through you
the big board, but I have this narrowed
down to a few options here. Kenyon
Sedeeq and Jer'Zhan Newton are both
still there. Those would be the hey,
it's not a necessary need, but but those
guys could be top five players in this
class when it's all said and done. Omar
Cooper Jr. is still there. Denzel Boston
is still there. Keanu Neal is still
there.
is still there. Is Tyson?
Um
Wait. Jordan Addison? Jordan Addison.
>> No, he was drafted
uh he went uh 11th to the Dolphins. Oh,
okay. Okay.
>> Yep. So, three receivers went fell,
okay. Three receivers off the board and
a lot of offensive linemen off the
board. So, we basically have our choice
of any wide receiver not the big three.
We could go Kenyon Sedeeq. We could go
Jer'Zhan Newton, a scenario that we just
discussed in the first hour of the show
for those who missed it.
>> Let me stop you there just I want to get
your opinion on this.
If you were to take one of those two,
Sedeeq or Newton, I [laughter] love
that.
>> Cuz we can eliminate one right off the
bat then.
I think Sedeeq is the one with the
higher ceiling.
Mhm.
I think Newton fits more of He's
certainly a more Cuz with Sedeeq
>> desired position across the league,
Newton.
>> With With Sedeeq right now,
Pat Freiermuth is what, 27? I mean, he's
hitting that tight end prime.
>> Yeah.
What if Muth settles in in this offense
and still has three or four really good
years ahead of him? And then you've got
Darnell who we think probably hasn't
even hit his peak as a tight end yet.
>> Right.
Sadiq could absolutely be better than
those two. That's not what I'm saying.
Whereas at corner,
yeah, I really like the signing of Dean,
but he's also going to turn 30 this
year. And he's had some injury stuff and
>> injury stuff.
>> Right. So, of those two, I think
I think I would
>> I think I would go with McCoy over
Sadiq.
>> Yes.
>> So, then it becomes McCoy or Maybe plays
out of position in the slot right off
the bat. You know, like
figure it out. You can do more stuff
with Ramsey, too.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Uh so, my logic then, I'm with you,
comes down to do I take McCoy or do I
like
Cooper Jr., Boston, or Concepcion? Who's
the best O-lineman available? The best
O-lineman available is Caleb Lomu.
For us though, I would take
Ekon Awhor over him. Blake Miller.
Miller I think is only a tackle.
>> Max Ena Awhor.
Okay.
>> it's those three.
>> it comes down to wide out versus McCoy.
Agreed. I would definitely consider Max,
but I'm fine saying we we take him all
the time, too.
>> Yeah.
I Hmm. I'd be very temp- I'd be very
tempted to take Omar Cooper Jr. here. As
well as Denzel Boston Boston and Casey
Concepcion. I like all three. Yeah.
Cooper's really good after the catch.
Little more physical. He just feels like
a different type than what they have in
in DK and
>> That's one of my issues with Boston.
He's a little redundant.
>> Yeah. He's a little samey as the guys
they have.
>> Yes, I agree.
>> And I don't think
One thing that McCarthy has mentioned,
especially this last week, is position
versatility. I don't know if I can put
Boston in the slot, you know, uh Metcalf
already isn't real slotty. Mhm. Um
I prefer Concepcion over Cooper. Do you?
Yeah.
>> hate that.
He brings a lot of juice to it.
>> definitely go those two over Denzel
Boston, for sure. Me, too. For this
team, for where they're at, yeah.
>> So, we have it narrowed down to Jamard
McCoy, Omar Cooper Jr., and Casey
Concepcion.
My vote's Concepcion.
I'm fine with that.
>> McCoy's fine. He's fine. I also wonder
though, like
how much of this
>> at receiver.
>> I don't want to be short at receiver.
And as much as I would love the luxury
pick, I wonder how much of this two is
just the mock simulators haven't caught
up with his rapid rise since his pro
day. Like, they have him ranked as the
18th overall prospect.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, that's not insane.
It's not, but I bet he
I mean, again, I don't think it's
cheating taking him here.
>> No, I don't I don't think so, either. I
Of all the kind of pie in the sky
scenarios that we had mentioned, I think
this one is semi-realistic.
>> too.
You want to go Casey Concepcion? I'm
fine with that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I like it. Let's go wide
receiver in the first round. We haven't
done much of that. And I'm good with him
or Omar Cooper Jr.
>> of heat around him now, too. He sure
does. He sure does. He might be the
fourth guy off the board. And we're
going to make him the fourth wide
receiver off the board for the purposes
of this
>> did my wide receiver ranks part two.
It's probably up on steelers.com today
or tomorrow.
Concepcion was my number two overall
wide out. Yeah? I mean, just
>> I love it. Well, then we definitely
should take him at pick 21.
>> It's just it's that's a generic ranking
for the league. That's I just think he
has a lot going for him.
Before we get to break here and uh and
and pick up in the second round on the
other side, here's how the rest of
everything shook out. Cayden McDonald
goes 22nd to the Chargers. Omar Cooper
23rd to the Eagles. CJ Allen to the
Browns. So, the Browns come away with
two Georgia guys in the first round with
Monroe Freeling
>> Yeah. Yeah. and CJ Allen. Uh Jamard
McCoy goes 25th.
Uh 26th, the Bills take Peter Woods. I
don't know if I could see that, but
Peter Woods goes 26th, the defensive
tackle out of Clemson. Caleb Lomu goes
to San Francisco. Man, I feel like
that'd be a real good succession plan
for them.
>> right?
>> Uh Denzel Boston goes 28th to the
Texans. Colton Hood goes
um 29th to Kansas City with the extra
pick that they got from the Trent
McDuffie trade. So, they bring in a
younger corner. Uh Blake Miller,
offensive tackle out of Clemson to the
Dolphins at 30. Uh TJ Parker, edge
rusher out of Clemson to the Patriots at
31.
And then the
uh let's see here. The Vikings trade up
to pick 32 with Seattle. Seattle gets uh
pick 49 and pick 82 out of the equation.
And the Vikings take Emmanuel McNeil
Warren, the safety from Toledo to close
to close down the first round. So, I
guess they missed out on Fenelon, come
back in at the end of the first round to
get Emmanuel McNeil Warren. Round two
kicks off. Remember the Browns picking
cuz they made that trade with the Dret-
the Jets. They take Brandon Ceaser, the
corner out of South Carolina. Ty Simpson
goes off the board at the Cardinals at
34. I think I think they would sign up
for that right now.
>> possible landing spot. Yeah. Lee Hunter,
defensive tackle out of Texas Tech, goes
35 to the Titans. So, I I know we made a
no trade rule.
And I know that it's also really hard to
trade up in these scenarios, but
I think people know my two biggest
crushes right now are Concepcion and my
man Max.
I would be on the phones like crazy as
day two started to try to get both those
dudes. And I don't think it'd be all
that hard. I mean, Especially when you
consider Max Ena Awhor didn't go till
pick 50 to Detroit.
>> what ended up happening? Just a couple
spots in front of the Steelers.
>> I definitely would have gotten somewhere
in the the
mid-30s, something like that. Like, if
you told me
I could leave this draft and it cost me
my my best third round pick,
my second and my first, and I got Max
and Casey, Sign for it right now.
>> Boom. Boom. And I don't think that's
nuts.
>> I don't think it is, either.
>> Right. And frankly, it could be Max and
Cooper or you know, if you do it the
other way around or whatever, you know
what I mean? That's why I'd love to
trade down a little in the first round,
get one of those dudes, and then trade
up heavy in the second round to get the
other one, you know?
Pregnon goes 38th to Houston. Rutledge
39th to the Browns. Little bit of a run
on offensive lineman.
>> Both of those hurt us bad. Yes. Caleb
Banks goes to the Chiefs at 40.
Christian Miller to the Bengals at 41.
Kenyon Sadiq all the way at pick 42. I
don't think
realistic, but the Saints would be doing
jumping jacks.
>> Yes. Uh Chris Johnson, corner out of San
Diego State to the Dolphins at 43. Chris
Bell to the Jets at 44. Trade and
Stukes, corner from Arizona to Baltimore
at 45. Anthony Hill Jr., linebacker from
Texas, goes to the Bucs at 46. Armon
Thomas, edge out of Oklahoma to the
Colts. Jeremy Bernard to the Bills.
Chase Bistineau to the Raiders.
>> I know.
>> The three guards,
>> I hate the picks right before the
Steelers. Bistineau, Ena Awhor to the
Lions. Chris Braswell to the Panthers.
Now, I don't think we would have gone
back-to-back wide receivers to start
this thing.
>> Braswell and Bell really intrigued me,
but I don't think we'd have gone
back-to-back. And Jacob Rodriguez goes
pick 52 to the Jags
>> Well, this went rough. to replace old
Devin Lloyd.
>> Man, I'd have been on the phone moving
up. Oh, I would have liked a lot of
those guys, certainly.
>> I thought for sure one of the three
guards. We We do We do have some some
offensive line options here though and
some some interesting options for pick
53. Let's take our first break of this
second hour and we'll pick this exercise
back up when we return. Wes Uhler, Matt
Williamson, little mock draft Friday
here on the drive. Steelers Nation Radio
on the Steelers audio network.
>> [music]
>> On the clock, pick 53 for the [music]
Steelers here. Second round, second
overall pick. We do not like how Boy,
that's been a rough second round for us.
>> rough second round for us, man.
>> especially the way things were fall-
Not only would I tried to trade up to
Max, like
Okay. So,
when we when we break on Thursday and
everybody goes home, puts their heads on
their pillow after one round of the
draft,
if I were in Omar's shoes, I would have
been calling to get to like 33, then 34,
35. I mean, like, what's it cost? I at
least want to test those waters.
But then, even after he fell, I mean, so
many of these dudes, I mean, the run of
the guard types and some of the guys we
really like,
I would have tried to have been
aggressive to even get up five spots,
you know, 10 spots, something like that.
And
I'm curious what's available cuz we got
hit hard.
>> We got hit hard. So, we got our wide
receiver, Casey Concepcion, in the first
round. But then a massive run on both
wide receivers and offensive lineman.
So, even if we would have taken an
O-lineman, we'd still I think be in the
same boat
just with wide receivers instead because
>> Yeah.
Let's take a look here. Wide receivers
still left. Antonio Williams, Zachariah
Branch, Ted Hearst, Elijah Serratt. And
I like those guys, but it might be a
little too soon. Might be a little too
rich here. Hearst is a guy I still have
a an eye out for in a big way, but the
those little slot types I don't think
are what the Steelers are after. No. And
really, Matt, in terms of interior
offensive lineman, the only guy that
really interests me here is Jennings
Dunker out of Iowa.
So, here's
>> Wouldn't be bad, but it's kind of a
consolation prize. Yes. I
>> I think he's a good player and he'd fit
in really well.
>> I would have loved Bistineau or Pregnon
or obviously Max.
>> Yeah. D'Angelo Pons still on the board.
Uh uh Eli Stowars, tight end out of
Vandy. AJ Housley, safety out of LSU.
Keonte Scott. Jake Galladay.
Uh Jadarian Wright.
>> Housley is interesting.
>> Yeah. Um
I
So, as I'm looking at this, I'm
interested in Housley. I'm obviously
interested in Jennings Duncker. Yeah.
And then I mean I know that Duncker
>> pure tackles? Uh,
not great.
>> really picked through.
>> Not great. Uh, Caleb Tiernan, Demetrius
Crownover, Austin Barber. Yeah. Those
are all third rounders.
>> Those are all third rounders.
>> So I think we go
we go a BPA type in Housley.
I don't think I'm going tight end here.
>> be our last chance to get a guy that
matters.
>> almost feel like you have to here. I do
or you almost have to punt on the O-line
for the
>> You got to punt on O-line at least for
guys that you think can immediately help
you.
>> Yeah. And And you don't get projects on
the O-line in the fourth round, you
know, like I think you almost have to
and I hate drafting that way, but if you
don't take Duncker here the way this
board went
you're not going to get one that's going
to help you. You're just not.
>> Completely agree. So let's do it. Let's
lock it in.
>> to. The Yinzers
>> not a terrible pick. It's just It's a
little underwhelming. Yeah, it's not I
wanted more options. Exactly right.
Exactly right. So
at pick 53 we go Jennings Duncker out of
Iowa. He'd fit in quite well on here.
>> fit in quite well. Eli Stowars finally
goes off the board to the Eagles at pick
54. Elijah Sorat 55 to the Chargers.
Uh, Igbinosun the corner out of Ohio
State. Ted Hurst goes 57th to the Bears.
Keaontay Scott at 58. Uh, Gabe Eickert
the edge rusher out of Illinois at 59 to
Houston. Malachi Lawrence edge rusher
out of UCF 60.
Um, to Chicago. Jake Galladay the
linebacker from Cincinnati comes off the
board to the Rams at 61. Finally RB2 at
pick 62 Jadarrian Price out of Notre
Dame and that would be what? 58 That'd
be 58 picks between the first and the
second running back taken.
>> I think that's about as early as RB2 can
fall. Seattle has such a need such a
need there. Yeah. Yes.
Uh, AJ Housley goes to the Patriots and
DeAngelo Pons goes to the Seahawks to
close down the second round.
Uh, Zachariah Branch leads off the third
round. Wide receiver out of Georgia.
>> Yeah, doesn't hurt us. Antonio Williams
wide receiver out of Clemson. Uh, to the
Titans. Keith Abney off the board from
Arizona State. Genesis Smith the safety
from Arizona. Uh, Malik Muhammad the
corner from Texas. Josiah Trotter goes
to the Giants. Ooh man, that would hurt
his dad's Philadelphia Soul.
>> Oh yeah, yeah.
>> That would hurt his dad's Philadelphia
Soul [laughter]
to see He's in the He's in the ring of
honor there and and for the Eagles and
his son ends up with the Giants.
>> Be like Joey Porter Jr. on the Ravens.
>> That would be exactly [laughter] right.
Or the Bengals or something.
>> Right.
Derrick Moore edge out of Michigan goes
to the Chargers. Joshua Joseph's edge
out of edge out of Tennessee to the
Bengals. Grayson Halton defensive tackle
out of Oklahoma to the Bears. Caleb
Tiernan offensive tackle out of
Northwestern to the Chiefs. And Sam Heck
the center from K-State goes to the
Commanders. So the Steelers on the clock
at pick 76 here.
You want to just
>> the Who's like the top 10 best
available?
>> Clark tight end from Ohio State. Mike
Washington running back from Arkansas.
Malachi Fields Notre Dame wide receiver.
Big Citrus. Dominique Orange defensive
tackle from Iowa State.
>> Darnell Jackson Jr. the defensive tackle
from Florida State that a lot of our
listeners keep tweeting us about how
much they love him.
>> Both those guys would make some sense.
Uh, Chandler Rivers corner from Duke.
Bryce Lance Trey Lance's younger brother
wide receiver out of NoDak North Dakota
State.
I guess NoDak is technically North
Dakota, but just roll with it. North
Dakota State. Uh, Camari Ramsey safety
from USC. Uh, Zakhari Whetley safety
from Penn State. Skyler Bell
>> Both those safeties too. Yeah. Uh,
Garrett Nussmeier still there. Kyle
Lewis still there. I don't know if the
Steelers going to have interest in
Simpson or Nussmeier. Just from again
reading the tea leaves of what McCarthy
was saying about size and big hands and
long arms and the physicality neither
one really fits that mold.
I am looking at the googly eyes here
Matt at Big Citrus Dominique Orange.
>> Mhm.
I don't know if I prefer him or the
Florida State D tackle. That's a good
question. I think they would prefer the
Florida State one just because of arm
length and the the style that they've
had.
>> a little more Yeah. Okay. That makes
sense and our our
our listeners would prefer that too. I
swear I swear we get a tweet about about
Darnell Jackson I feel like almost every
single day. Must be a lot.
>> saying that's a bad thing. Lord have
some Seminole alumni.
>> They must have some must have some
Seminoles out there in Steeler Nation.
So I'd be looking at those two defensive
tackles. I think this is a little too
early to go running back as much as I
I'd be intrigued by getting by getting
RB3. Um, but I'd be looking at those two
defensive tackles and probably the two
safeties. Camari Ramsey and Zakhari
Whetley. Exactly. I was thinking the
exact four names.
Um, I'm trying to think outside the box
here. Is there anybody else that's
What's an off the ball linebacker
situation?
Kyle Lewis if you count him there.
Deonte Lawson from Alabama.
>> Aidan Fisher from Indiana.
No. Uh, Keishawn Elliott from Arizona
State.
>> the other four better for sure.
>> I'm looking at I'm looking at I think
this might be the time to take Darnell
Jackson.
It's fine with me. We haven't done it
yet. Fits the position I think it's him
or Big Citrus I feel like here. You want
to do it? Let's do it. Yeah, again this
isn't
There's others if we even if we get shut
out on these two safeties with our next
pick there's more safeties to pick from.
There aren't many D tackles I care
about.
>> Bud Clark from TCU still out there.
Yeah, yeah there's other ones that would
fit the mold at least.
>> back on the clock in just nine picks.
>> say we
chances are we'll get one of them
>> So let's go Darnell Jackson Jr. Let's go
to the D-line here.
>> wouldn't have a problem with Orange
either.
Neither would I. Neither would I.
Um, we've taken him in past exercises
around this location. Max Clark goes off
the board after us to the Bucks. Malachi
Fields to the Colts. Uh, Chandler Rivers
out of Duke. Jacoby Lane the wide
receiver
>> Rivers a lot. I I don't know if they're
interested in like a smaller slot only,
but he's feisty and good. Jacoby Lane
the wide receiver out of USC goes to the
Ravens at pick 80. Zakhari Whetley comes
off the board at pick 81 to the Jags.
>> Okay. Mike Washington the Seahawks
finally get their running back at the at
the front end of the third round here.
Uh, Danny Dennis Sutton edge rusher from
Penn State 83 to the Panthers. And
Keiron Crawford edge out of Auburn 84 to
the Packers. So one of our options was
still there. So Big Orange and Camari
Ramsey both made it here. Bud Clark is
still there Matt as is Kyle Lewis if you
kind of
you know Any more of a free and powerful
guy?
>> Camari Ramsey feels like
kind of fell right into our lap. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Let's do it. The first thing
that kind of went our way. Let's do it.
I like it.
We'll lock him in there at pick 81 and
then again I mean we're back on the
clock here not to uh pick 85 pardon me
and then we're back on the clock just 14
picks later. We're doing four rounds,
right?
>> doing four. We are doing four rounds.
Yes. So let's see here after we picked
Camari Ramsey. Michael Trigg one of my
draft crushes goes to the Dolphins. Oh,
I was going to say I thought you were
going to say he's available. I was like
I could be convinced there.
>> to him here.
Um,
so the Dolphins get another talented
upside pass catcher. Big Citrus finally
goes off the board pick 89 to
Jacksonville. Uh, Big Citrus ended up in
Florida. Imagine that.
>> Yeah, isn't that lovely?
>> out well?
Uh, Bud Clark goes at pick 90 to the
Dolphins.
Uh, Kyle Lewis the local guy goes 92 to
the Cowboys.
Uh, Bryce Lance goes 93 to the Rams.
Let's see here. Jaylen Farmer the guard
from Kentucky 94. Skyler
>> pretty good player too. Yeah, he would
have been one of the ones that I might
have entertained if we wouldn't have
>> Yeah, yeah, yeah. Uh, Skyler Bell wide
receiver from UConn goes to the Patriots
at 95. Jake Slaughter center from
Florida to the Seahawks. Another Penn
State guy off the board at 97. The
tackle Drew Shelton to the Cardinals.
And then the Eagles take at pick 98
Julian Neal the corner from Arkansas. So
quick reminder. Yeah. At pick 21 we took
wide receiver Casey Cole Sepuchi. 53
Jennings Duncker the guard from Iowa. 76
Uh, Darnell Jackson Jr. defensive tackle
from Florida State. And then Camari
Ramsey safety from USC at 85. So we do
have a nice two offense two defense. Two
guys in the trenches. A wide receiver
and a safety. So I think we're pretty
open here Matt for whatever. Um, and
here's some of the best names on the
board.
>> my original thoughts for this pick is
I would consider an off the ball
linebacker. Um, a name
as a a name we don't bring up enough is
a name who I forget is the Arizona State
linebacker. I like him an awful lot and
feel like he is a value in the third
round.
>> Yes. I have not heard his name yet. I
think he's
Okay. He's definitely
somebody I have my eye on in this draft
more and more.
>> Him, Aidan Fisher, Deonte Lawson your
top rated linebackers still available.
>> take Arizona State over those other
dudes.
>> Okay.
Uh, Demetrius
and offensive lineman here. just going
to say
Demetrius Crownover is still here out of
A&M.
Uh, Austin Barber out of Florida still
on the board.
>> from Miami. Let's see.
He is. Yes. Markel Bell, Jude Lowry,
Isaiah World, Austin Barber.
>> guy I like too. And Demetrius Crownover
for your offensive line.
>> Crownover is a nice project as a left
tackle.
>> Okay. Um
I mean you can convince me if the a
certain receiver was still there, but I
think those names got hit pretty hard.
>> They have. Brennan Thompson, DeShawn
Zrieling, Deon Burks, Kevin Coleman Jr.,
Kendrick Law. Nah.
And I would also consider a great tight
end or a great running back. I mean
great's a big word in this part of the
draft.
>> Sure. Sure. Justin Jolly, Eli Rerdon,
Daylen Bentley. Most of the big name
tight ends are gone.
Running backs Emmett Johnson from
Nebraska is still there. Keaontay Allen
from Penn State is still there.
I I interested in both of them.
>> with the linebacker. I think I would go
with a linebacker or a tackle based on
how this is. Me too. So, we can go let's
see tackles again Demetrius Crownover,
Markel Bell, Austin Barber, Isaiah
World, Jude Bowery.
Line
>> of those names. Okay. Linebackers Deonte
Lawson, Aiden Fish. You like Keyshawn
out. So, I feel like it's Keyshawn
Elliott or one of those tackles.
Now we we pick again We pick again in 22
picks and then 135 as well.
>> on one being there, but So, we have two
more picks after this.
I think I'd take the linebacker. I think
the tackles are still a little more
flush. Yeah.
>> where I would lean linebacker.
>> get dry. I'm sure they'll get soaked up,
but I can live with that.
>> go Keyshawn Elliott.
>> Yep. I you know, made some friends with
some Arizona State guys at the baseball
game while we were there. Very fitting
for where we're coming from, right?
>> picking their brain on on all those
guys.
Uh and so let's do it. Let's let's let's
take a linebacker Keyshawn Elliott out
of Arizona State at pick 99.
So, we have two more picks left 121 and
135.
There was a little bit of a run on on
some offensive lineman here.
>> I bet. And on some linebackers as well
too. Crownover is off the board. Garrett
Nussmeier is off the board. Aiden Fisher
off the board. Austin Barber off the
board. Markel Bell off the board. I
would have loved him to have been
around.
>> grab him there. And so we are back on
the clock at pick 121. Let's do this.
Let's take our last break of the day.
Okay. On the other side we'll close down
the fourth we'll close down the fourth
round with our last two picks. I'll lay
out the big board for everybody and our
options that remain. Wes Uhler, Matt
Williamson one more leg to go here on a
mock draft Friday.
It is the drive Steelers Nation Radio on
the Steelers Audio Network.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Final segment here on this Friday. Final
segment today and of this week and we
are closing things down in style with
our annual Friday mock draft that we'll
continue to do. Only a couple more weeks
here Matt until we get to the real
thing. It's all happening quickly in the
off season. It always does. Little you
always think oh off season so much time.
>> Oh no, 20 days away from the draft.
>> have a coaching change and the combine
and the owners meetings and the draft
and all of a sudden it's like wait
summer time already. How did this all
happen? And we're going to have a
beefier off season than usual too with
some extra practices and things allowed
with a new head coach. But before we get
to any and all of that.
>> Quick rundown. What do we got so far?
>> Yes. KC Conceição wide receiver Texas
A&M, Jennings Dunker guard out of Iowa,
Darrell Jackson Jr. defensive tackle
from Florida State, Kamari Ramsey safety
from USC, and Keyshawn Elliott
linebacker from Arizona State. So,
some of these we didn't love how the
board fell for us.
>> No, I mean I think I'm going to go fish
on this draft probably. Yeah, I think
so. I certainly think so. But in terms
of the positions, I think the positions
lined
>> up nicely with what we would like to
come away with with our premium picks
here. But we have two more to make 121
and 135 before we close down this
exercise. Matt, you want
>> What quarterbacks are available? Ooh,
I like that. So, Nuss has gone Okay, so
basically three quarterbacks off the
board so far. Mendoza obviously, Ty
Simpson obviously. Nuss went at the very
beginning of the fourth round fifth pick
in the fourth round to the Giants.
Um so, Carson Beck, Drew Allar, Taylen
Green, Cole Payton
Would you consider Green or Payton?
Yes. They're the only two I'd consider
just because the upside's massive on
both.
They both were reportedly in for visits
or going to be.
>> Yes. You know what's funny about that
too. I mentioned to you how it just
seemingly randomly I don't know randomly
or just I don't know if it's standing
out to me. Whatever the case may be, but
it feels like we've got a lot of tweets
about Darrell Jackson Jr. in the last
week. Mhm. I feel like all of a sudden
people are starting to tweet us about
Taylen Green a lot too. Really? I
haven't noticed it, but okay. Well, you
you probably to be fair get a lot more
tweets than I do, but I do my best to
pay attention, but I'd be interested in
one of those two here just as a pure
project sit him on the back burner for
an entire year or see where you're at.
Now, let me ask you this though cuz we
are back on the clock in just 14 picks.
Yeah. So, let's see if we would do that
now or try and wait and then
>> Yeah, yeah. I'm not married to it. Yeah.
So,
um let's see here. Tight end Eli Raridon
out of Notre Dame leading off the big
board. DeShawn Zribling the wide
receiver from Old Miss still there.
Okay. Um Isaiah World the tackle out of
Oregon still there. Emmett Johnson
running back out of Nebraska still
there. He's the player. I I he's the one
I'm looking at.
>> out, yeah.
>> Unless you tell me that you really like
Isaiah World because I know there's a
lot of varying opinion on him. I think
that's Some people think he's like a day
two talent. And he was a super recruit,
but he doesn't play that way. Yeah, I
think he's got an injury. I was just
going to say he's he was a super recruit
who never really lived up to the billing
and he's doesn't have the best bill of
health either.
>> Yeah, yeah. Um I'm I'm looking
>> Emmett Johnson's pretty appealing. I
think Emmett Johnson's very appealing
here. That I think is without spending a
ton of time thinking this through
anyway.
>> like oh you don't need a running back,
but you're one Jaylen Warren injury away
from being really thin in week three at
running back. And then all of a sudden
do you believe in Caleb Johnson? I mean
How could you write the second say yo
yeah, I definitely do. I think that's
the pick.
>> it's the pick too. Good receiver too. If
you're telling me that you know, into
the fourth round your sixth pick you
could get a quality running back. Good
out of the backfield
>> trust have him as running back two. I I
was going to say I've seen I've seen him
as high as mocked in the second round by
some people that we trust. Let's take
him here in the fourth round.
>> Okay. Emmett Johnson out of Nebraska
with our penultimate pick of this
exercise. DeShawn Zribling goes off the
board. Isaiah World goes off the board.
Eli Raridon goes off the board. Harold
Perkins Jr. the linebacker that we've
discussed a little bit out of LSU.
>> in his neighborhood and they're throwing
him in the mix and see what happens.
>> He goes to the Lions at 128.
Um and then yeah, back on the clock at
135. All those quarterbacks that we
mentioned still there. Hasn't been
another quarterback taken Matt.
Um just real quick for the for the for
the here's the other the other people
that are still available.
>> Yeah, I'd say the the two quarterbacks
are appealing.
Uh Charlie Demings the corner out of
Stephen F. Austin.
>> him quite a bit too. I was I thought
that was a name you had mentioned to me
at some point. There's still running
good running backs available obviously,
but we're out of that market. Jude
Bowery still there. The tackle out of
Boston College. I think he's got a
chance to be a a starter. Uh Joe Royer
tight end out of Cincinnati.
>> right? We have not. Um no, we have not.
Only offensive lineman we've taken was
Jennings Dunker at 53. I would take
Bowery or Demings over the two
quarterbacks. I think I would too
because you this is only the fourth
round. You still
you still have
>> Only three quarterbacks been drafted.
You still have five picks after this and
there's only been three quarterbacks
that have been drafted. And frankly, you
could trade up and get one of those
quarterbacks easily if you wanted to.
It's it's funny you say that cuz I was
like oh we'll definitely take a
quarterback. I mean Dante Corleone still
there. We're not going that route cuz
we've already taken a defensive tackle.
Um Would you rather go tackle or corner?
I would just simply ask you of Jude
Bowery and Charlie Demings who you think
has a better chance to be a full-time
starter in two years.
Demings just cuz tackles are tough. It's
true. But if if Bowery hits and is a
starter, I I I frankly think Bowery's
going to be your your swing tackle.
>> guy. Which is valuable. You know what
I'm right?
>> Sure.
Either one would be fine with me.
I probably go Deming. I think Demings is
probably the better prospect. Okay.
Let's see if any of these other corners
you'd be willing to wait on. Yeah.
Ezequiel Mathis out of California.
Uh Devin Marshall out of NC State.
Thaddeus Dixon out of North Carolina.
Uh Andre Fuller out of Toledo. Demani
Jackson out of Alabama. Those are the
top ranked corner
corner still available.
No.
I think Demings is noticeably better
than those guys.
>> Let's do it. That works for me. Let's
lock it in.
I'm cool with that. There's our
exercise. And man, we came away with all
different positions. We didn't double up
anywhere. We made seven picks. These
last like five picks have been good. I
just didn't love how the first two were.
Well, Conceição I was fine with, but I
just we didn't have a lot of options in
the We didn't have a 53. We didn't quite
have the options that we wanted to, but
that's why you do these exercises.
>> Yeah, yeah. Not every pick's going to go
to plan. So, KC Conceição wide receiver
out of A&M at 21, Jennings Dunker guard
out of Iowa at 53, Darrell Jackson Jr.
defensive tackle from Florida State at
76, Kamari Ramsey safety from USC at 85,
and Keyshawn Elliott linebacker from
Arizona State at 99, and then into the
fourth round we take Emmett Johnson
running back out of Nebraska, and then
we take Charlie Demings corner out of
Stephen F. Austin at 135.
>> Okay. Our four round Friday mock here
on the drive.
You know, the one thing though that we
didn't do is I mean I guess we'd still
have three rounds to do so, but we got
to draft somebody in in these mock draft
exercises you got to draft somebody from
Indiana.
That's what they do, right? Yeah. Three
years of drafting Omar Khan has drafted
four guys from national championship
teams in in three years. There's
something about winning. I mean yeah. Um
It was his very first pick in Broderick
Jones. Roman Wilson was a national
champion, and then of course Jack Sawyer
and Howard. and Will Howard. So, four in
three years
one one and two. So, we'll see if that
trend continues, but this was this was
fun for kind of our kind of our Friday
exercise here.
>> It's good going through them. Yeah, you
suck at
I at least like this one I liked because
it was
it this played out much differently than
all the other time. Very different,
right?
>> we've we've had A lot of different
decisions
>> of different decisions. We thought about
McCollum in the first round. Yeah, we
did. Right. How different would this
have been if we had And Saddiq. Yeah,
yeah, yeah. Yeah, so I I I think that's
I think that's good. I'd love to get
Concepcion in here though.
I'm a fan. He'd be a punt returner right
now.
>> Are you Are you Are you at the point
where you would trade 21 for that or
maybe not just quite?
>> so. Yeah? I think so. I like that
confidence that you have though. That
makes me feel better about
I'm a big
>> option to pick options at pick 21.
>> I I think this draft sets up really well
21. That there's going to be five guys
I'd be real comfortable with that will
probably be sitting there. And then from
53 you wish you could just get up to
like 40.
45.
>> Yeah, it's true. You always can.
>> three thirds and two fourths you could
definitely get up if you want. It's
going to be going to be a lot of fun to
see how it all plays out but that will
do it for us for today.
>> It has been a good week. We're
enjoyed our time in Phoenix but
certainly happy to be back. Happy to be
back with our guy Mr. TV, Tyler V.
Shoutout to him on the video side of
things today. Easter weekend? Easter
weekend, yeah, everybody if you're
traveling,
um, be safe out there as we always tell
you when it's holidays and gathering
time.
Uh, grab your family members phones,
subscribe to the Steelers YouTube page,
subscribe to all of our, uh, different
podcast platforms, you know, the, uh,
the drive on, uh, Apple podcast and
Spotify and Google and all that good
stuff.
>> phone.
>> Grab grandma's phone, subscribe to us in
four or five different places and she'll
be very thankful that you did so.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh, that'll do it for us this week. Next
week back to studio, back to regularly
scheduled programming. Thanks to
everybody who's been rocking and rolling
with us throughout the off season and we
will obviously continue to ramp up the
draft conversation but that will do it
for us today. Thanks to TV. Thanks to
Matt Williamson. I'm Wes Uhler. Take
care everybody, enjoy the weekend, be
good and we'll talk to you next week. As
always you know where to find us. It's
on your 24/7 home of the black and gold,
Steelers Nation Radio on the Steelers
Audio Network.
What's up NFL fans? The NFL Draft is
finally here and while you might not
know who your team is [music] drafting
this year, you do know your watch
party's number one pick, Bud Light. The
clean, crisp taste that has all the
scouts talking. Guess that's why it's
been the group's go-to draft beer season
after season. Be sure to order a round
for the table before your team's on the
clock. Bud Light, [music] easy to drink,
easy to enjoy. Enjoy responsibly.
Anheuser-Busch Bud Light Beer, St.
Louis, Missouri.